## David Bengoa

Software Engineer

Email: <u>david@bengoa.me</u>

Github: <a href="https://github.com/dvdbng">https://github.com/dvdbng</a>

About Me

Very experienced software engineer.

Constanyly learning. Will take a messy codebase and slowly turn it into a properly arquitected codebase. Great at debugging and finding simple solutions to hard problems.

I'm most experienced in Python, Javascript and Rails

## Experience

Welcome
Technologies
Senior Software
Engineer

Ongoing since 2017

Welcome Technologies delivers educational content for Hispanic immigrants and connects them with services. I have helped scale Welcome Technologies form 400k users to 1.4M, while decreasing infrastructure costs, improving platform speed, stability and security, while being one of two engineers in the team.

Scrapinghub
Software Engineer
2015 - 2017

Amune.org
Co-founder and CTO
2014 - 2015

Scrapinghub provides a cloud-based web crawling platform, off-the-shelf datasets, and turn-key web scraping services.

With immunity zone, my team and I pushed the boundaries of the web as a platform by implementing a fully-featured browser that runs in the cloud. The backend loads the page and executes the JavaScript on it, sending the result to the client. The result is a secure, private and

## faster browser that can run inside any modern browser.

CERN
Invenio Developer
(Intern)
2013

Invenio is an Open Source project that powers the CERN Document Server and INSPIRE, the HEP Database that contains bibliographic records of more than one million publications and that replaced SPIRES, the first website outside of Europe and the first database to be served over the web.

## Education

University of Málaga

Software Engineering

2009 - 2012

Graduated with honors (best of class) in Object oriented Programming, Data structures, Analysis and Design of Algorithms, Formal Languages and Automata Theory, System Programming/Concurrency and Operating Systems.

Southampton Solent

BSc (Hons) Soft. Eng.

2012 - 2013

Two semesters abroad

David Bengoa - <u>david@bengoa.me</u> - References on request